<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Troubleshooting on Hiren Patel</title>
    <link>https://patelhiren.com/categories/troubleshooting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Troubleshooting on Hiren Patel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright {year}, Hiren Patel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 20:11:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://patelhiren.com/categories/troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Catalina and Skype for Business Screensharing</title>
      <link>https://patelhiren.com/blog/catalina-and-skype-for-business-screensharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 20:11:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patelhiren.com/blog/catalina-and-skype-for-business-screensharing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After upgrading to macOS Catalina (10.15.4), Screensharing via Skype for Business stopped working. Here is waht I did to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After upgrading to macOS Catalina (10.15.4), Screensharing via Skype for Business stopped working. Here is waht I did to fix it.</p>
<p>macOS Catalina introduced new Privacy settings that prevents Skype for Business screensharing to work if proper permissions are not provided. On trying to start Screensharing via <strong>Conversations-&gt;Share Screen</strong> option, Skype would display a message stating check the <strong>Skype For Business</strong> option under <strong>System Preferences-&gt;Security &amp; Privacy-&gt;Privacy Tab-&gt;Screen Recording</strong>. However navigating there did not display &ldquo;Skype For Business* as an option.</p>
<p>To correct it I first reset the &ldquo;Screen Recording&rdquo; permissions for Skype by running this command on Terminal.</p>
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code><span class="lnt">1
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-zsh" data-lang="zsh">tccutil reset ScreenCapture com.microsoft.SkypeForBusiness
</code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div><blockquote>
<p>If you do not provide the <strong>com.microsoft.SkypeForBusiness</strong> identifier, the Screen Recording permissions for all apps will be reset and you will have to provide permissions again as needed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>After running that command. I relaunched Skype, selected a Conversation and tried sharing via the screen via the menu option again. I got the same error I got earlier from Skype and no Screen Recording permission prompt was displayed by the OS.</p>
<p>I had to select the &ldquo;Share Screen&rdquo; icon on the top right of the conversation window. When I tapped that, the OS permissions prompt for Screen Recording came up. I gave the required permission, restarted Skype and was successfully able to share my screen.</p>
<p><em>For the record this was on Skype for Business version 16.28.175.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>